Guide to the Keith Botsford Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1890-1968; Series II; 25.03 linear feet (65 boxes)
  - Articles
    - Other Articles
      - "Bonus March," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 70)
      - "Brazil," typescript and typescript carbon, 1963 (Box 70)
      - "Brazil's New Language," typescript and printed material, 1962 April (Box 70)
      - "Elections in Peru," typescript, 1962 June 15 (Box 70)
      - "Europe and America," typescript and typescript carbon, 1962 (Box 70)
      - "Gaullism and the Hemisphere," typescript and typescript carbon, 1964 (Box 70)
      - "The Glorious Spring Revolution," typescript and typescript carbon, 1962 (Box 70)
      - "Ibargüengoitia Translation," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 70)
      - "Intellectuals and Cultural Freedom," typescript, 1962 March (Box 70)
      - "Intellectuals in Latin America," typescript and typescript carbon, 1963 (Box 70)
      - "Kazin," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 70)
      - "Lowell," typescript, 1962 (Box 70)
      - "A Mexican Original," typescript, undated (Box 70)
      - "Mexican Presidency," typescript and typescript (photocopy), 1963 (Box 70)
      - "Music in Mexico," typescript, undated (Box 70)
      - "New Statesman Letter," typescript, 1963 March (Box 71)
      - "Nist," typescript, 1963 January (Box 71)
      - "Reflexions on Kennedy," typescript carbon and printed version, 1964 (Box 71)
      - "Rousset Translation," typescript, undated (Box 71)
      - "Saul Bellow," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 71)
      - "Shades of Vargas," typescript, 1962 (Box 71)
      - "Shapiro 'Invisible Man' Commentary," typescript, 1963 (Box 71)
      - "Succession in Spain and Portugal," typescript and printed version, 1963 (Box 71)
      - "The 39 Articles," typescript, undated (Box 71)
      - "Why Karol Falls," typescript, undated (Box 71)
      - "Wilson," typescript, undated (Box 71)
      - "Youth in Latin America," typescript and typescript carbon, 1963 (Box 71)
      - Materials on Borges, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 72)
      - Records and talks with Gilberto Freyre, 1962 (Box 72)
      - Genet article, printed version, undated (Box 72)
      - Materials for a survey of press attitudes, undated (Box 72)
  - Early Fiction and Short Stories
    Not arranged in any particular order.
    - "Frederick Delius," novel fragment, typescript, 1946 (Box 73)
    - "He and Edourd," autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, 1945 (Box 73)
    - "Problem Child," notebooks, 1940-1941 (Box 73)
    - "The Room Beyond," notebooks, 1940 (Box 73)
    - Short stories, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, 1940-1941 (Box 73)
    - "Valentine," autograph manuscript draft, undated (Box 73)
    - Unidentified typescript fragments, undated (Box 73)
    - Drawings, undated (Box 73)
  - Essays
    - "Appollinaire," typescript, undated (Box 74)
    - "The Baron in the Trees," review, typescript, 1959 (Box 74)
    - "La Demoiselle Edue," typescript and autograph manuscript drafts, undated (Box 74)
    - "Fool's Paradise," review, typescript, 1959 (Box 74)
    - "Graffiti," typescript, undated (Box 74)
    - "A Matter of Jurisdiction," autograph manuscript, typescript and printed material, undated (Box 74)
    - "Menen Review," typescript, undated (Box 74)
    - "Montcalm & Wolfe," typescript, undated (Box 74)
    - "Pavese Review," typescript, 1959 May (Box 74)
    - "Playboy Article," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 74)
  - Notebooks
    - Notebooks, undated; 4 (Box 75)
  - Poems
    - "Introductory material," by C. Sammons, 1968 (Box 76)
    - Notes & rough drafts for poems, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1943-1946 (Box 76)
    - Poems, typescript drafts, 1943-1946 (Box 76)
    - "The Age of Bronze: Twelve Pagan Choruses," typescript and typescript carbon, 1943-1946 (Box 76)
    - Poem cycles, autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, 1944-1945 (Box 76)
    - Notes and drafts for poems, autograph manuscript, 1944-1947 (Box 76)
    - Poems, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, 1944-1947 (Box 76)
    - Poems, autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, 1945 (Box 76)
    - "The Still Graves," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, 1945 (Box 76)
    - "Le Prince D'Aquitaine. Sonnets," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, 1945 (Box 76)
    - "Seven Elegiac Lamentations," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, 1945-1946 (Box 76)
    - Poems, autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, 1947 (Box 77)
    - Poems, typescript carbon drafts, 1947 (Box 77)
    - Poems, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, 1947 (Box 77)
    - "Lyric," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon notes and drafts, 1949 (Box 77)
    - "Poem for Harvey's Birthday," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon notes and drafts, 1949 (Box 77)
    - "Two love-songs," autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, 1949 (Box 77)
    - "Atlantic City," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon notes and drafts, 1950 (Box 77)
    - "Eight Poems," typescripts, 1955-1961 (Box 77)
    - Poems and drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 77)
    - "Naomi: a play in two acts," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon drafts, undated (Box 77)
    - "Quintet: a monologue in five parts for a wood quintet," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 77)
    - "XI. A Temptation of St. Anthony. The Minor St. Anthony," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon notes and drafts, circa 1945 (Box 81)
    - "XVIII. Elegy for Joseph Freeborn," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carobn notes and drafts, 1949 (Box 81)
    - "XIX. The Plague," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon drafts and notes, 1948-1949 (Box 81)
    - "XXV. Simulacrum," typescript, undated (Box 81)
  - Screenplays
    - The Eternal Husband, typescipt and typescript carbon, 1947 (Box 78)
    - "The Twelve Year Cycle," scenario for a film, typescript and typescript carbon, 1945-1947; 3 (Box 78)
  - Translations
    - Aub, Max, "A Few Exemplary Crimes," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 79)
    - Denjoy, Paul, "AN-NAM: Doctors & Sorcerors..." translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Huard, Pierre. "The Blackening of Teeth in Eastern Asia and Indo-China," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Jeanselme, E. "Medicine and Doctors According to the Annamite Code," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Kressen, P. "The Annamite Community in Cochin China," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Labussiere, _____. "A Study of Rural Landowning in Cochin China," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Mihajlow, Mihajlo, "Moscow Summer 1964," translation by Keith Botsford, typescript, undated (Box 81)
    - Monod, G. H. "The Cambodian," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Poreé, Guy and Éveline Maspero, "Customs and Traditions of the Khmers," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Richard, _____. "Notes to Serve for the Ethnology of Cochin China," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Sallet, A. "The Thuôe mê, Mysterious Drugs of the Bandits of Annam," and "The Ngai, the Magic Plants of Southern Annam," translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 79)
    - Partial and unidentified translations pertaining to China and the Far East, undated (Box 79)
  - Writings of Others
    - Anonymous, Review of Benvenuto by Keith Botsford, typescript and printed versions, 1961 (Box 80)
    - Botsford, Charles Hull
      - Bibliography of works concerning steam navigation, typescript, undated (Box 80)
      - "Catalogue of Books," typescript, 1890 (Box 80)
      - Excerpts, typescript, undated (Box 80)
      - "Fultons First Steamboat," typescripts with drawings, undated (Box 80)
      - "Invitations sent...," autograph manuscript, undated (Box 80)
      - Untitled works concerning steam navigation, typescript, undated; 3 (Box 80)
      - Printed articles and clippings collected by C. H. Botsford, undated (Box 80)
    - Botsford, Robert K. Printed advertisements for coins, "Poems Worth Remembering," pamphlet, 1964, undated (Box 80)
    - Ibargüengoita, Jorge, "Revolucion en el jardin." typescript carbon, undated (Box 80)
    - Peyre, Henri, "Report on K. Botsford's MA Essay," typescript carbon, 1952 May 7 (Box 80)
    - Pixon, Nelida, "Aventura de saber," typescript carbon, 1963 (Box 80)
    - Zand, Nicole. Paper given at UNESCO conference, typescript carbon, 1965 (Box 80)
- Other Papers, 1937-1968; Series III; 2.30 linear feet (7 boxes)
  Series III consists of correspondence, reports and questionaires related to the International PEN conference in Bled, Yugoslavia in 1965, and financial and personal papers spanning 1937 to 1968.
  Organized topically.
  - International PEN
    - Materials related to conference in Bled, Yugoslavia, 1965; 4 (Box 82)
    - Materials related to conference in Bled, Yugoslavia, 1965; 4 (Box 83)
    - Unsorted documents and correspondence, 1965; 7 (Box 84)
  - Financial Papers
    - Finances and accounting, 1950-1951 (Box 85)
    - Finances and bank statements, 1958-1960 (Box 85)
    - Bank deposits and statements, 1959-1962; 3 (Box 85)
    - Bank desposits and statements, 1962-1964 (Box 85)
    - Household expenses, Brazil and Mexico, 1962-1964; 2 (Box 86)
    - Accounts, receipts, correspondence, and unused checks, 1964-1965; 2 (Box 86)
    - Insurance and Fairfield Foundation Grant, 1965 (Box 86)
    - Payments to Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1965 (Box 81)
    - Accounts, 1966 (Box 86)
    - Other financial papers, 1968 (Box 86)
  - Memorabilia, including certificates, report cards, programs, and printed ephemera, 1937-1965; 2 (Box 87)
  - Diary fragment, 1944-1945? (Box 87)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 87)
  - Rolled Photograph, undated (Box 88)
- October 1964 Acquisition, 1906-1963; Series IV; 6.88 linear feet (17 boxes)
  Arranged alpabetically by subject or title. Existing order has been maintained. Unsorted and unidentified material is filed at the end of the group.
  The October 1964 Acquisition consists of writings and subject files. Writings include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, and notes. Subject files relate to writing projects (or planned projects) and include notes, clippings, photographs and printed material.
  - "Acts & Galatea: Marino. Gongora. Carillo. Montalvan." autograph manuscript and typescript, 1951 (Box 89)
  - "Alain-Fournier," typescript, 1906 July 31 (Box 89)
  - "Amer. Literature," autograph manuscript and typescript, 1952, undated (Box 89)
  - Argument for Man, typescript and "The Earthquake," abandoned Part I of Argument for Man, typescript, undated; 4 (Box 89)
  - "Artificiality: The Greek Romances," typescript, undated (Box 89)
  - "Arts" article, autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon, 1958 (Box 89)
  - "Atlantic City," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 89)
  - "Bard College," autograph manuscript and typescript notes and course materials, undated; 4 (Box 90)
  - "Baroque (general)," typescript notes, undated (Box 90)
  - "Ben Bellit," typescript and typescript carbon essays, 1950-1952 (Box 90)
  - "Black Grapes," review, autograph manuscript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 90)
  - "The Blessed Demoiselle," typescript, undated (Box 90)
  - "The Bounder," typescript and typescript carbon, 1956 (Box 90)
  - "Bring on the Girls," typescript, undated (Box 90)
  - "Burkha," typescript, undated (Box 90)
  - Carey's End, typescript carbon, undated; 2 folders (Box 91)
  - "Christianity and Communism," autograph manuscript and typescript carbon, 1945-1946 (Box 91)
  - "Cinematography," autograph manuscript notes, undated (Box 91)
  - "Claudel and Hopkins: The Magnificat and The Wreck of the Deustchland ," autograph manuscript and typescript carbon, 1936-1944 (Box 91)
  - "CBS," autograph manuscript and typescript notes and correspondence, 1957 (Box 91)
  - "Comedy," essays, autograph manuscript and typescript carbon notes and drafts, 1949 (Box 91)
  - "The Crux," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 91)
  - "Cuba," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 91)
  - "Cymbalum Mundi," by Bonaventure des Periers, translated by Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 91)
  - "Dante," autograph manuscript and typescript notes, undated (Box 91)
  - "The Dead, As They Lie," typescript, undated (Box 91)
  - "Democracy," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 91)
  - "Democrats," typescript, undated (Box 91)
  - "Egyptology," typescript, 1953 (Box 92)
  - The Eight-Best-Dressed Man in the World, typescript and proof, 1957 (Box 92)
  - "Empson," typescript notes, undated (Box 92)
  - "End of a Renaissance," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 92)
  - "Esquisse Three," typescript, undated (Box 92)
  - "Essays, ideas, notes and drafts," typescript, undated; 2 (Box 92)
  - "Existence of God," autograph manuscript and typescript, 1943 (Box 92)
  - "The Expert on Marriage," typescript, 1956 (Box 92)
  - "The Foley Square Marathon," typescript, 1949, undated; 2 (Box 92)
  - "Freeborn, Elegy for Joseph," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 92)
  - "Gaugin," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon notes, drafts, and translations, 1948-1952; 9 (Box 93)
  - "Genet," autograph manuscript and typescript notes and drafts, undated; 3 folders (Box 93)
  - "Germany," autograph manuscript, typescript and printed materials, undated (Box 93)
  - "Good Enough," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon, 1953 (Box 94)
  - "Guicharnaud," typescript carbon, undated (Box 94)
  - "Guilloux-Palante Translation," original typescript and translation, 1926, undated (Box 94)
  - "Gulliver," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon materials, undated; 8 (Box 94)
  - "Hierens," typescript and newspaper clippings, 1946 (Box 94)
  - "Hopkins," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 94)
  - "Hue, Art In," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 94)
  - "Hunters After Hunters," autograph manuscript, undated (Box 94)
  - "Italian Translations: Coreno de Medici, etc." autograph manuscript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 94)
  - La Bar, Tom. "Boil On Fair Potato," "Eula," and "The Illness of Anthony Pomeroy," typescripts, undated (Box 94)
  - "The Land-owner," typescript, 1955 (Box 94)
  - "Lawrence," typescript notes, maps and other printed materials, undated (Box 95)
  - "Leopardi (translations)," autograph manuscript and typescripts, 1953 (Box 95)
  - "Leont'yev translation," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 95)
  - "Long After Love," typescript mimeograph and printed materials, undated (Box 95)
  - "Love Show," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon notes, photographs, and printed material, undated (Box 95)
  - "Machiavelli," typescript notecards, undated (Box 95)
  - "Magazine Ideas," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 95)
  - "Margaret of Navarre," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 95)
  - "Master Race," autograph manuscript and typescript film synopsis, undated (Box 95)
  - "Mauriac translations," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 95)
  - "Milton," typescript, undated (Box 95)
  - "Monster Colony," typescript, undated (Box 95)
  - "Movies," typescript, photographs and printed materials, undated; 3 folders (Box 96)
  - Museum of Modern Art pictures, photographs, undated (Box 96)
  - "Nardi," autograph manuscript notes and newspaper clippings, 1947 (Box 96)
  - "The Negro Question in the United States," typescript, 1943? (Box 96)
  - The New Leader and New University articles, printed versions, 1960, 1963 (Box 96)
  - "The Night Rider," typescript, undated (Box 96)
  - Noble Savage 4, galley proof, 1960 (Box 96)
  - "Not a Funny Story," typescript, undated (Box 96)
  - Notebook, 1944 (Box 96)
  - Notes and Notebooks, undated; 3 (Box 97)
  - "On the State of Literature: A Catholic Position," typescript, 1949 (Box 97)
  - "Pascal," autograph manuscript and typescript notes, undated (Box 97)
  - "Pere Noël: The Life of Noël Chabonel," typescript, undated (Box 97)
  - Perleman, S. J. "The Changing Ways of Love," typescript mimeograph, 1957 (Box 97)
  - "Philosophy," autograph manuscript notes, undated (Box 97)
  - "The Pillars of Hercules," autograph manuscript and typescripts, 1956-1962, undated; 3 (Box 97)
  - Plays, untitled, typescript carbon, undated; 2 (Box 97)
  - "Poem from a story by Katherine Anne Porter," typescript, undated (Box 97)
  - "A Possession for the Bittern," typescript, undated (Box 98)
  - "Principles of Religious Reflection," typescript, 1945 (Box 98)
  - "Proust," notebook, undated (Box 98)
  - "Radio," autograph manuscript and typescript, 1948, undated (Box 98)
  - "Reply to Malraux," typescript, 1955 (Box 98)
  - "Retalbo," typescript, 1957 (Box 98)
  - "Rilke," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 98)
  - Rutenborn, Gunter. The Sign of Jonah. A New Version by Keith Botsford, typescript, typescript carbon, and typescript mimeograph drafts, 1957; 4 (Box 98)
  - "School," autograph manuscript and typescript, 1958 (Box 99)
  - "Sculpture," printed images, undated (Box 99)
  - "The Second Life of Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart," typescript, undated (Box 99)
  - "Seven Elegiac Lamentations," typescript carbon, undated (Box 99)
  - "The 'Seven Lively Arts,'" typescript and printed materials, 1955-1957; 2 (Box 99)
  - "Shakespeare," notes and newspaper clippings, and programs, 1955-1957, undated; 4 (Box 99)
  - Short stories, autograph manuscript and typescript drafts, undated (Box 99)
  - "Show Ideas," typescripts, undated (Box 99)
  - "Sketches and Developments," typescript and autograph manuscript, undated (Box 99)
  - "The Somnambulist," typescript and typescript carbon, 1947 (Box 99)
  - "Soutine," typescript, undated (Box 99)
  - "Stendhal: The Artist's Vanity," typescript, 1950 (Box 99)
  - "Stratford 'Times,'" typescript, undated (Box 99)
  - "TV Ideas (plays)," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 100)
  - "10-13 CM," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 100)
  - "Theory, etc.," typescript notes, undated (Box 100)
  - "The Thirty-third Mandarin," typescript, undated (Box 100)
  - "The Three Agonies," typescript carbon, undated (Box 100)
  - "Translations," autograph manuscript and typescript, 1946-1950; 3 (Box 100)
  - "Ultima Thule," typescript, undated (Box 100)
  - "Valery, Paul," autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon, undated; 6 (Box 100)
  - Von Kleist, Heinrich. Translations by Keith Botsford, typescript carbon, 1955; 3 (Box 101)
  - "The Wedding," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 101)
  - "Whodunit," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 101)
  - "World's Time," autograph manuscript notes, 1955 (Box 101)
  - "YPR," autograph manuscript and typescript notes, undated (Box 101)
  - Unidentified materials, undated; 4 (Box 101)
  - Personal and financial papers, 1945-1955; 11 (Box 102)
  - Unsorted materials, undated; 20 (Box 103)
  - Unsorted materials, undated; 4 (Box 104)
  - Unsorted materials, undated; 4 (Box 105)
- December 1965 Acquisition, 1958-1960; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  The December 1965 Acquisition consists of subject files and drafts of writings, including translations by Botsford.
  Arranged roughly alpabetically by title or subject. Existing order has been maintained.
  - University of Puerto Rico, correspondence and unidentified writings, 1958-1960 (Box 106)
  - "Aria: Islands in the Sun," typescript, undated (Box 106)
  - "Aria: On Abolitionists...," autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 106)
  - Benvenuto forward, typescript, undated (Box 106)
  - "Carted Off," typescript carbon, undated (Box 106)
  - "Controversy: And the Lion...," typescript carbon, undated (Box 106)
  - Guilloux, Louis. "Romganons," translation by Keith Botsford, typescript carbon, 1959 (Box 106)
  - Leulliette, Pierre. "Adventures of a Parachutist," translation by Keith Botsford, typescript, typescript carbon, and correspondence, 1959 (Box 106)
  - Noble Savage, related materials, undated (Box 106)
  - " Poetry of Georges Palante Introduction," translation by Keith Botsford, typescript carbon, undated (Box 106)
  - "Some Small Beginnings," typescript, undated (Box 106)
  - "Why Karol Falls," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 106)
  - Unidentified writings, autograph manuscript, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 106)
  - School papers, undated; 3 folders (Box 106)
  - Printed material, undated (Box 106)
- November 1969 Acquisition, 1961-1967; Series VI; 2.09 linear feet (5 boxes)
  The November 1969 Acquisition consists chiefly of drafts of writings, including drafts and other material related to The Index.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject or title. Existing order has been maintained.
  - "Aitken," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 107)
  - "Amado," typescript and autograph manuscript notes, undated (Box 107)
  - "American Aristocracy," typescript, 1967 (Box 107)
  - "Anatomy of a Party," typescript carbon, undated (Box 107)
  - Berlin - Keith Botsford's article for festival on poetry, "In Defense of Love and Pronouns: Some Reflexions on the Themes of Modern Poetry," typescript mimeograph and photocopy, 1964 (Box 107)
  - Borges, typescript and typescript carbon writings and notes, undated (Box 107)
  - "Cadernos Brasileiros," typescript, undated (Box 107)
  - "Carted Off with Flowers," typescript, undated (Box 107)
  - "C.C.F.," typescript, 1964 (Box 107)
  - "Fuentes," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 107)
  - "Glanville," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 107)
  - "Grass on Brecht: A Profile," typescript, undated (Box 107)
  - The Index
    - Drafts, typescript, corrected, undated; 5 (Box 108)
    - Drafts, typescript, corrected, undated; 4 (Box 109)
  - Articles from The Index
    - "Airports," typescripts, undated (Box 110)
    - "Christmas Eve," typescript, undated (Box 110)
    - "Jews," typescripts, 1967 (Box 110)
    - "Laura's Idyll," typescript (photocopy), undated (Box 110)
    - "The Lovely L.," typescript, undated (Box 110)
    - "Marriage," typescript carbons, undated (Box 110)
    - "A Member of the Delegation," typescript, 1966 (Box 110)
    - "Sunday and Sabbatha," typescript, undated (Box 110)
    - "Youngers and Olders," typescript, 1967 (Box 110)
  - "A Letter from the Provinces of Mexico," typescript, 1965 (Box 111)
  - "The Moralist in the Province," by Carol Fuentes, typescript, undated (Box 111)
  - "The Old Belief," typescripts, 1965; 3 folders (Box 111)
  - "Out in the Styx," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 111)
  - "P.R.I. History and Material Reference," typescript, typescript carbon and printed materials, undated (Box 111)
  - "Parade," typescript and typescript carbon, 1965 (Box 111)
  - "PEN," typescript, 1965 (Box 111)
  - "Poland," autograph manuscript and typescript drafts and printed version, 1966 (Box 111)
  - "Reflexions on Kennedy," typescript carbon, undated (Box 111)
  - "The Thirty-Nine Articles," typescript (photocopy), 1962 (Box 111)
  - "Tolstoi Lecture," autograph manuscript and typescript, 1961 April (Box 111)
  - "Venezuela," typescripts, undated (Box 111)
  - "Venice," typescripts, 1967 (Box 111)
  - "Why Students in France Go Communist," typescript drafts and printed version (photocopy), 1966 (Box 111)